

Brian D. Harris

User Experience (UX) Researcher and Designer 801-414-8652 | uxbrianharris@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/brian-harris-research

Summary

Expert mixed-methods researcher and user experience specialist. Vast repertoire of both qualitative and quantitative methodologies and techniques. High-productivity, low-maintenance problem-solver for complex challenges. Creative idea generator with strategic insight. Excellent communicator, coordinating proactively and reporting clearly. Fluent in Spanish. Motivated by client trust and relentlessly pursuing user satisfaction. Strong record of learning new skills. Able to offer cross-disciplinary assistance in research, design, product development, and analytics.

Skills

- Design thinking
- Poignant user insights
- Focus groups and interviews
- Survey and experiment design
- Journey mapping
- Jobs-to-Be-Done methods
- Iterative product development
- Wireframes and prototypes

- Usability testing
- Agile sprint testing
- Adobe XD, Figma, Miro, Invision, Storyboarder
- SPSS, Stata, Excel
- Visual data storytelling
- Fluent in Spanish

Professional Experience

UX Researcher and Strategist | Purple Innovations | 2020-present

Embedded in the e-commerce department and working alongside designers, merchandisers, and copy writers to continually improve the experience of visitors to the site and drive sales.

- Organized an ongoing series of in-depth interviews with a variety of audience segments at different points in the customer journey.
- Consulted with staff and executives on various new product launch strategies.
- Used research to help guide transitions to a new checkout system and a new visual style for the entire site.

Senior Researcher | Boncom | 2019-2020

Director of research for entire ad agency. Led simultaneous high-profile projects with minimal supervision.

- Managed internal and external data collection to steer rebranding Tabernacle Choir at Temple Square, including new logos, taglines, organizational values, purpose statements, and brand promises.
- Informed creative strategy for Utah Department of Health initiatives:
 - o Live On, suicide prevention campaign
 - o Stop the Opidemic, substance abuse resources and support
 - o Zero Fatalities, safe driving initiative
- Researched expected offerings, naming, logos, style and tone for www.skylight.org. Organized and launched beta tests with recurring panel of app users. Informed web experience design.
- Supervised research for an online university to understand its students, motivations for enrolling, current experiences, and marketing opportunities.
- Directed research to guide management transfer of LDS Church historic sites. Produced clear guiding principles for the Historic Sites Division and creative recommendations for improved visitor experience.
- Conducted ground-breaking visitor experience research among non-member "secret shopper" visitors to the LDS Church. Pilot tested new church products intended to help welcome newcomers and visitors.

Study Lead and Researcher | LDS Church Research Division | 2013-2019

Senior researcher with responsibilities in study planning, vendor management, panel management, survey administration, project management, and delegation to junior colleagues. Frequent client consultation.

- Repaired strained interdepartmental relationships while coordinating multiphase international test pilot for youth activity program. On-time global implementation lauded by executives as "miraculous."
- Directed international pilot research for new seminary curriculum to guide development. Evaluated implementation fidelity and objectives and offered human-centered recommendations.



uxbrianharris@gmail.com



801.414.8652



linkedin.com/in/ brian-harris-research

- Strengthened interfaith partnerships by leading an international study among Muslim-born converts to explore messaging for new publication for use in humanitarian efforts in Muslim-majority countries, highlighting shared values.
- Provided qualitative and quantitative feedback regarding missionary mobile device training. Piloted mobile device roll-out leading to fully operational global program with more effective proselyting and fewer behavior problems.
- Provided insights into convert retention by designing a longitudinal study to identify when and why individuals stop attending, with actionable suggestions.
- Administrated Qualtrics license for over 1,500 employees. Consulted across organization on survey design and methodology. Developed standard procedures for research division to oversee studies throughout organization.

Instructor | UC Irvine and Brigham Young University | 2010-2012

Taught seven upper-level university courses in probability, statistics, research methods, data analysis, and data presentation. Developed course curricula. Tutored individual students and led study group sessions.

Education

Currently enrolled: Online UX/UI Bootcamp | University of Utah Completion in Feb 2021

Master of Science (MS), Sociology | Brigham Young University | 2011 Emphasis on statistics and quantitative methods, qualitative methods, inequality, immigration, and digital communication.

Progress toward PhD, Sociology | University of California, Irvine | 2011-2012 Completed required coursework. Left program for full-time applied research career. Specialized in statistics, research methods, communication, immigration, and inequality.

Bachelor of Science (BS), Sociology | Brigham Young University | 2009 Emphasis on research design, statistics, and research methodology.







Publications

Harris, B. D. and T. L. Goodsell. 2011. "Family Life and Marathon Running: Constraint, Cooperation, and Gender in a Leisure Activity." Journal of Leisure Research 43(1): 80-109.

Harris, B. D., C. V. Morgan and B. G. Gibbs. 2013. "Evidence of Political Moderation over Time: Utah's Immigration Debate Online." New Media & Society 16(8): 1309-1331.

T. L. Goodsell, **B. D. Harris**, and B. W. Bailey. 2013 "Family Status and Motivations to Run: A Qualitative Study of Marathon Runners." Leisure Sciences 35(4): 337-352.





